Imagine a smart TV developer claims to collect
summarized data to their server once a week.
How can outsiders validate this claim, while
the TV, the communication, and the server
are all black-boxes?
In this paper, we ask how to help developers
avoid collecting unnecessary data and make
it transparent.
We introduce peekaboo, a new architecture
that leverages an in-home hub to pre-process
outgoing data.
In Peekaboo, developers create a data collection
manifest using a fixed set of chainable operators.
The hub then assembles and executes a pre-processing
pipeline using operators pre-loaded on the
hub.
In doing so, developers collect only necessary
data; outsiders can verify data collection
behaviors; and the hub can offer built-in
privacy features.